We've seen that we use a Markov decision process or
我们刚刚介绍了我们可以使用
MDP as a formal definition of
马尔可夫决策流程 (MDP)
the problem that we'd like to solve with reinforcement learning.
正式地定义想要通过强化学习解决的问题
In this video, we specify a formal definition for the solution to this problem.
在本视频中 我们将指定该问题解决方案的正式定义
We can start to think of the solution as a series of actions
我们可以将解决方案看作
that need to be learned by the agent towards the pursuit of a goal.
智能体为了实现目标必须学会的一系列动作
For instance, in order to walk,
例如 为了行走
the humanoid robot needs to learn the appropriate way to apply forces to its joint.
类人机器人需要学习向接合处应用力的合适方式
But as we've seen, the correct action changes the situation.
但是我们知道 正确的动作会随着状况而改变
If a robot encounters a wall,
如果机器人遇到墙壁
the best series of actions will be different than if it had nothing blocking its path.
一系列最佳动作与道路畅通无阻时会不一样
Reward is always decided in the context of the state that it
奖励始终由作出决策时遇到的状态
was decided in along with the state that follows.
及其之后的状态决定
With this in mind, as long as the agent learns
因此 只要智能体学会根据
an appropriate action response to any environment state that it can observe,
它能够观察的任何环境状态作出合适的动作响应
we have a solution to our problem.
我们就拥有了问题的解决方案
This motivates the idea of a policy.
这就要提到策略这一概念
The simplest kind of policy is a mapping from the set
最简单的策略是从一组环境状态
of environment states to the set of possible actions.
到一组潜在动作的映射
In case you're new to the idea of a mapping,
如果你不熟悉映射概念
you can think of a policy as a factory that takes any environment state
可以将策略看做一个工厂
as input and outputs the corresponding action that the agent will take.
工厂将环境状态作为输入 并将智能体将采取的相应动作作为输出
If the agent wants to keep track of its strategy,
如果智能体想要跟踪策略
all it needs to do is to build this factory or to specify this mapping.
它只需构建该工厂或指定该映射
We call this kind of policy a deterministic policy.
我们将这种策略称之为决定性策略
Income is the state,
输入是状态
outcome is the action to take.
输出是要采取的动作
And as you can see,
可以看出
it's most common to denote the policy with the Greek letter pi.
通常将策略表示为希腊字母 π
Another type of policy that we we'll examine is a stochastic policy.
我们将了解的另一种策略是随机性策略
The stochastic policy will allow the agent to choose actions randomly.
随机性策略使智能体能够随机地选择动作
We define a stochastic policy as a mapping that accepts an environment state S and
我们将随机性策略定义为以下映射
action A and returns the probability that the agent takes
接收环境状态 s 和动作
action A while in state S. For clarity,
并返回智能体在状态 s 时采取动作 a 的概率
let's revisit the recycling robot example from the previous lesson.
为了进行阐述 我们再看看上一节课的回收机器人示例
The deterministic policy would specify something
决策性策略将指定为
like whenever the battery is low, recharge it.
每当电量很低时 则充电
And whenever the battery has a high amount of charge, search for cans.
每当电量很高时 则搜索易拉罐
The stochastic policy does something more like whenever the battery is low,
而随机性策略则是
recharge it with 50 percent probability,
每当电量很低时 充电概率是 50%
wait where you are with 40 percent probability.
等待概率是 40%
And otherwise, search for cans.
搜索易拉罐的概率是 10%
Whenever the battery is high,
每当电量很高时
search for cans with 90 percent probability.
搜索易拉罐的概率是 90%
And otherwise, wait for a can.
否则等待有人扔进易拉罐
It's important to note that any deterministic policy can be expressed
需要注意的是 任何决策性策略
using the same notation that we generally reserve for a stochastic policy.
都可以采用随机性策略通常用到的同一记法
For instance, this policy can be expressed as,
例如 这个策略可以表示为
whenever the battery is low,
每当电量很低时
recharge it with 100 percent probability.
充电概率是 100%
Whenever the battery has a high amount of charge,
每当电量很高时
search for cans with 100 percent probability we will explore
搜索易拉罐的概率是 100%
policies with varying levels of randomness or stochasticity in this course.
我们将在这门课程中了解随机性等级各不相同的策略
Now, at this point you might be wondering.
现在你可能会疑问
Now that we know how to specify a policy,
我们已经知道如何指定策略
what steps can we take to make sure that the agent's policy is the best one.
应该采取什么样的措施来保证智能体的策略是最佳策略？
We will work towards answering this question in the next few concepts.
我们将在接下来的几个部分回答这一问题